Finding Aid for the The Robert Burns Eleazer Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
The Robert Burns Eleazer Papers
undated
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0129
1.68 linear feet
Biographical Sketch
Robert Burns Eleazer (1877-1973) was born in Bellsburg, TN. He attended Southwestern Presbyterian University in Clarksville, TN and received his B.A in 1898 and his M.A. in 1899. In 1910, he married Ethel Fleming; they had three children.
After college, Eleazer tried several occupations that were to prepare him well for his later work. In 1900, he became a candidate for the Prohibitionist Party and, soon thereafter, a teacher in a one-room schoolhouse. After becoming a journalist in Clarksville and editing several small local newspapers, he was asked, in 1907, to join the Tennessee Anti-Saloon league as a Field Worker and editor of their official paper The American Issue. In 1909, he moved to Nashville to work as Office Secretary for the Laymen’s Missionary Movement, an agency of the Southern Methodist Board of Missions. For the next thirteen years he worked for the Mission Board of the Methodist Church, editing their official magazine The Missionary Voice. This period also saw the beginning of his anti-war activism, as he opposed the US entry into WWI. Due to his involvement in the Methodist Church’s Movement for Revision, an effort to limit the power of Bishops and make the church more democratic, his contract was not renewed in 1922.
Eleazer was then asked by his friend Dr. Will Alexander to move to Atlanta to work as Education Director for the Commission on Interracial Cooperation. He worked tirelessly for the CIC for twenty years until 1942, when the organization was restructured into the Southern Regional Council. Mr. Eleazer then returned to Nashville where he spent the next seven years as “Special Worker in Race Relations” for the Methodist General Board of Education until his retirement.
Scope and Content Note
The Robert Burns Eleazer Papers (1877–1973) include correspondence and writings by Eleazer as well as newspaper clippings, course and program outlines, press releases and pamphlets. There are several autobiographical writings as well as a transcription of Mr. Eleazer being interviewed by historian John Egerton shortly before Mr. Eleazer’s death in 1973. Writings by others include reviews, articles, pamphlets and student papers.
Eleazer’s manuscripts are divided into several series including Methodism and Christianity, Anti-War writings, writings on Economic and Political Issues in the South and, most prominently, Race Relations. Within the Race Relations series is a subseries on Education which includes material from Eleazer’s twenty years as Education Director of the Commission on Interracial Cooperation as well as his subsequent five years as Special Worker in Race Relations for the Methodist Board of Education. This series includes outlines for courses and programs on race relations at the college, high school and adult education level. Additionally, the collection includes a large scrapbook containing extensive documentation of Eleazer’s years with the Methodist Board of Education. Letters, essays, clippings and pamphlets make this a fascinating document of civil rights work in the 1940’s. The Eleazer Papers also include press releases from both the Commission on Interracial Cooperation and the Methodist Board of Education and a collection of pamphlets and brochures produced by the CIC for their educational efforts in the South.
The Papers consist of 4 Hollinger boxes (1.668 linear feet) and one flat box containing a large scrapbook. The bulk of the materials come from the 1920’s through the late 1940’s.
- Correspondence – Incoming
  - Adams, Sherman (The White House), 2 (1953) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alexander, Will Winton (Commission on Interracial Cooperation, Office of Production Management War Manpower Commission), 8 (1922, 1941-43, 1950) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Armstrong, O. K., 1 (1941) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ashley, Albert (Henry Street Settlement), 1 (1933) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Atkins, F. L. (The Winston-Salem Teacher’s College), 1 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Atkinson, Henry A. (World Alliance for International Friendship through the Churches), 1 (1921) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Barnett, R. Ira, 1 (1940) (carbon; original to Ludd M. Spivey) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bass, Ross (United States Senate), 1 (1966) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bayless, W. P. (Pittsburgh Courier), 1 (1944) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Beaird, Pat (Abingdon-Cokesbury Press), 1 (1949) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Beauchamp, Luke G. (General Board of Education of the Methodist Church), 1 (1950) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bell. W. A. (Miles College), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bell, William H. (Alcorn A & M College), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bethune, Mary McLeod (National Youth Administration), 2 (1942-43) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bludworth, G.T. (Texas State Department of Education), 1 (1928) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bond, H. M. (The Fort Valley State College), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Boss, Charles F., Jr. (Commission on World Peace), 1 (1946) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Braddy, Haldeen (Texas Christian University), 1 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brasfield, T. W. (Harrison-Stone-Jackson Agricultural High School and Junior College), 1 (1939) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brearley, H. C. (Clemson Agricultural College, George Peabody College for Teachers), 6 (1938-39, 1942-43, 1947) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brigham, G. R. (Brenau College), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brockman, Fletcher S., 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brown, Ernest E. (State of Oklahoma Department of Public Instruction), 1 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brown, Walter M., 1 (1941) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Browning, Gordon (Tennessee Executive Chamber), 2 (1950-51) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brownlee, Fred L. (The Board of Home Missions of the Congregational and Christian Churches), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bryan, William Jennings, 1 (1916) (with 3-page signed manuscript ,“Christian Preparedness,” with holograph revisions) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Buffington, Willie L. (Faith Cabin Library), 4 (1933) (to Will W. Alexander; with one clipping, 6 photographs, and 2 typed manuscripts, “The Story of My Life” and “How Faith Cabin Came into Existence”) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bullock, R. W. (YMCA), 1 (1929) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Burroughs, Nannie H. (National Trade and Professional School for Women and Girls), 1 (1943) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Byrns, Joseph W. (House of Representatives), 4 (1919-22) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Caldwell, Millard F. (State of Florida Executive Department), 1 (1946) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Caliver, Ambrose (Federal Security Agency), 2 (1943, 1953) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Camp, Cordelia (Western Carolina Teachers College), 1 (1941) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cannon, T. Carlisle (Methodist Episcopal Church, South), 1 (1932) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Capper, Arthur (United States Senate), 1 (1941) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Carney, Mabel (Rural Education), 1 (1929) (to W.W. Alexander) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Carney, Mabel (Columbia University), 2 (1931-35) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Carr, I. N. (Mars Hill College), 1 (1941) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Carruth, J. E. (South Georgia Teachers College), 1 (1939) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Carver, George Washington (Tuskeegee Normal and Industrial Institute), 1 (1931) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Chappell, Joe (United States Senate), 1 (1939) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Choate, Cautious A. (The Central Kansas Conference Board of Education), 1 (1948) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Clark, Elmer T. (Board of Education, M E. Church, South), 1 (1922) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Clark, J. L. (Sam Houston State Teachers College), 1 (1943) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Clark, J. S. (Southern University), 1 (1943) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Clarke, Edwin L. (Rollins College), 1 (1943) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Clement, Rufus E., 1 (1943) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cole, William E. (The University of Tennessee), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Comer, Harry F. (University of North Carolina), 1 (1925) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cook, Howard (Department of State), 2 (1953-54) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Coxe, John E. (State of Louisiana Department of Education), 1 (1938) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Crippen, Lee F. (Berea College), 2 (1939) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cromley, B. F. (Saluda County Supt. of Education), 1 (1933) (to Will Alexander) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cummings, Thomas L., Jr., 1 (1966) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cuninggim, J. L. (Scarritt College for Christian Workers), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Currie, Thomas W. (The Austin Presbyterian Theological Seminary), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Dabney, Virginius (Richmond-Times Dispatch), 1 (1944) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Daniel, J. McT. (University of South Carolina), 1 (1941) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dannelly, C. M. (Montgomery Public Schools), 1 (1943) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Davage, M. S., 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Davidson, Alan (British Embassy), 1 (n.d.) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Davis, Jackson (Central Education Board), 3 (1942-43) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Derbigny, I. A. (Tuskeegee Institute), 1 (1950) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dixon, J. C. (Mercer University), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dorsey, Hugh M. (State of Georgia Executive Chambers), 1 (1921) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dowell, Spright (Mercer University), 2 (1939, 1941) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Downs, Mrs. J. W. (Board of Missions and Church Extension of the Methodist Church), 1 (1943) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dunkle, John L. (State Teachers College, Frostburg, Md.), 1 (1939) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Edmonds, Henry M. (Rollins College), 1 (1943) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Edwards, Helen (Biloxi Public Schools), 1 (1937) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Edwards, W. T. (State of Florida, Department of Education), 1 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Eisenberg, Larry (The General Board of Education of the Methodist Church), 1 (1945) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1 (1952) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ellison, Virginia F. (Missionary Education Movement of the United States and Canada), 1 (1944) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Embree, Edwin R. (Julius Rosenwald Fund), 1 (1943) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Eppse, Merl R. (Tennessee Agricultural and Industrial State College), 1 (1933) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ethridge, Mark (The Courier-Journal & The Louisville Times), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Franstead, N. (American Relief Administration Children’s Fund), 1 (1919) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Frost, Norman (George Peabody College for Teachers), 1 (1941) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Fugate, Mary C. (Averett College), 1 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Fulbright, J. W. (United States Senate), 1 (1966) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Fulton, Richard (House of Representatives), 1 (1966) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Garrison, S. C. (George Peabody College for Teachers), 1 (1943) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - George, Walter F. (United States Senate), 3 (1940-41) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Gerber, Joe N. (Northwestern State College), 1 (1948) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Gilliard, Edward Madison, 1 (1920) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Gilrow, William E., 1 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Glenn, C. B. (Board of Education, Birmingham, Ala.), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Gore, Albert (United States Senate), 3 (1953, 1966) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Granberry, John C. (The Emancipator), 2 (1939) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Gratz, W. E. J. (The Epworth Herald), 1 (1939) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Greeley, George, 1 (1939) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Groves, Charles P., 1 (1931) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Gunn, W. Fred (West Georgia College), (1943) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Hammaker, W. E. (The Methodist Church, Denver Area), 1 (1948) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Harap, Henry (George Peabody College for Teachers), 1 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hargraves, Corliss P. (The Joint Department of Missionary Education, The Methodist Church), 1 (1948) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Harlow, Ralph (Smith College), 1 (1941) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Harris, Edward D., Jr. (Arkansas Senate), 1 (n.d.) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Haygood, W. C. (South Georgia Teachers College), 1 (1939) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Haynes, George E. (The Federal Council of the Churches of Christ in America), 2 (1943) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hays, Brooks (House of Representatives), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hearon, Murvise (Jena High School, La.), 1 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Helms, F. Clyde (Shandon Baptist Church), 1 (1943) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hill, Lister (United States Senate), 1 (1945) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hill, Sylvia (Tennessee Women’s Christian Temperance Union, Work among Negroes), 1 (1931) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Holden, Queen (United States Senate, Office of Senator George), 2 (1938-39) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Holley, J. W. (Georgia Normal and Agricultural College), (1939) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Horst, Edna C., 1 (1932) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hubert, Benjamin F. (Georgia State College), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Humphrey, Hubert H. (The Vice President), 1 (1966) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hunt, R. L. (Magnolia Public Schools), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Jackson, W. C. (University of North Carolina, Greensboro), 2 (1942-43) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - James, Mrs. W. C. (Women’s Missionary Union), 1 (1929) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Jeter, Olyve L., 1 (1943) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Jett, L. B., 1 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Johnson, Charles S. (Fisk University), 2 (1942-43) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Johnson, F. Earnest (Federal Council of the Churches of Christ in America), 1 (1922) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Johnson, Glenn R., 1 (1937) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Johnson, Mordecai W. (Howard University), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Jonas, Richard O. (Hardin Junior College), 1 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Jones, Laurence C. (Piney Woods School), 1 (1933) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Jones, M. Ashby, 1 (1943) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Jones, Robert E. (The Methodist Church, New Orleans), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Jones, Thomas E. (Fisk University), 5 (1942-43) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Jones, Thomas Jesse (Phelps-Stokes Fund), 5 (1942-43) (one each to Jackson Davis and S.C. Mitchell) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Kahn, Julius M. (Anti-Defamation league of B’Nai B’Rith), 1 (1948) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Keech, Vera M. (Supervisor of Schools, Colbert County, Ala.), 1 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Keel, Martha Kathryn, 1 (1938) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Kefauver, Estes (United States Senate), 6 (1950, 1952-53, 1957-58) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Keith, Roger (Life Magazine), 1 (1965) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Kern, Paul B. (The Methodist Church, Nashville Area), 2 (1948, 1951) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - King, William Peter (Christian Advocate), 1 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - King, Willis J. (Gammon Theological Seminary), 3 (1942-44) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Knobbs, Pauline D. (Northeast Missouri State Teachers College) 2 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Lambert, J. S. (State of Alabama, Department of Education), 1 (1941) (with 1 clipping) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Lane, J. F. (Lane College), 2 (1921, 1933) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Latture, R. N. (Washington and Lee University), 1 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Libby, Frederick J., 1 (1941) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Loescher, Frank S. (Randolph-Macon Women’s College), 1 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Lowrey, Lawrence T. (Blue Mountain College), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Lynch, Frederick (The Christian Work, Save the Children Fund), 1 (1920) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Lyon, Ralph M. (The Citadel), 1 (1928) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Mangun, Vernon L. (Mary Hardin-Baylor College), 1 (1941) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Marshall, Peter (British Embassy), 1 (1953) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Martin, Mrs. Attwood (Association of Southern Women for the Prevention of Lynching), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Martin, Paul E. (The Methodist Church, Ark. La Area), 1 (1948) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Mason, Lucy R. (Congress of Industrial Organizations), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Maston, T. B. (Southwestern Baptist Theological Seminary), 1 (1943) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Mays, Benjamin E. (Morehouse College), 2 (1942, 1948) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - McDowell, Edward A. (Southern Baptist Theological Seminary), 1 (1943) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - McGeacy, D. P. (Decatur Presbyterian Church), 1 (1938) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - McKellar, Kenneth (United States Senate), 6 (1919-20, 1922, 1946-48) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - McPherson, N. C., Jr. (Wesleyan College), 2 (1943) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Meyer, Harold D. (University of North Carolina), 2 (1939) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Mitchell, George S. (Southern Regional Council), 2 (1955) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Mitchell, S. C. (University of Richmond), 2 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Moffat, Pierrepont (Department of State), 1 (1938) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Moore, Fred Atkins (Emergency Peace Campaign), 4 (1936) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Moreland, J. Earl (Randolph-Macon College), 1 (1943) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Morgan, Laura (Time Incorporated), 1 (1965) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Morton, Nelle (Executive Committee of Religious Education and Publication), 2 (1944) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Mullin, James P. (Emergency Peace Campaign), 1 (n.d.) (to Carl Atkins) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Myers, James (The Federal Council of the Churches of Christ in America), 3 (1943-1952) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Myers, Joseph (Emergency Peace Campaign), 1 (1936) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Nelson, Mrs. Claud (Emergency Peace Campaign), 1 (1937) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Newbold. N. C. (State of North Carolina, Superintendent of Public Instruction), 2 (1942-43) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Nutter, H. E. (University of Florida), 1 (1939) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Odum, Howard W. (University of North Carolina, Commission on Interracial Cooperation), 5 (1942-44) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - O’Neill, Patrick (St. Bernard College), 1 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Page, Stephen (House of Representatives), 1 (1941) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Page, Kirby (Emergency Peace Campaign), 3 (1936) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Patten, Arthur B., 1 (1933) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Patterson, F. D. (Tuskeegee Institute), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Patton, Leslie K. (Tusculum College), 1 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Paty, Raymond R. (University of Alabama), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Payne, Bruce R. (George Peabody College for Teachers), 1 (1933) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Phipps, W. E. (State of Arkansas, Department of Education), 1 (1933) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Pierce, Lucile (Wesleyan Foundation), 1 (1948) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Piney Woods Country Life School, 1 (1939) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Pinson, W. W. (Board of Missions, Methodist Episcopal Church, South), 4 (1922) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Poole, Frederick G. (Board of Christian Education), 1 (1943) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Potts, J. Manning (Greene Memorial Methodist Church), 1 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Priest, J. Percy (House of Representatives), 8 (1944, 1946-48, 1952) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ramspeck, Robert (House of Representatives), 7 (1938-41) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Raper, Arthur (U.S. Department of Agriculture), 1 (1943) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Read, Florence M. (Spelman College), 3 (1933, 1943-44) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Reid, Rebecca (South Carolina Committee on Interracial Cooperation), 1 (1943) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Reynolds, J. H. (Hendrix College), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Reynolds, Julia R., 1 (1938) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Rhodes, E. Washington (The Philadelphia Tribune), 1 (1928) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Rice, John A. (First M.E. Church, South), 1 (n.d.) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Richardson, Harry V. (Tuskeegee Institute), 1 (1939) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Richardson, M. L. (The Macon Daily Telegraph), 1 (1924) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Rittenhouse (Southern Junior College), 1 (1939) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Roberts, A. H. (Governor of Tennessee), 1 (1919) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Robertson, Frank L. (Glenn Memorial Methodist Church), 1 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Russell, Daniel (Agricultural and Mechanical College of Texas), 2 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Russell, Richard B., Jr. (United States Senate), 8 (1939-41) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - St. Patrick, Sister Mary (Our Lady of Victory College), 1 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Sanders, Irwin T. (Alabama College), 1 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Sanford, Gilbert A. (University of Mississippi), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Scarborough, J. R. (Dept. of Public Schools, City of Jefferson), 1 (1933) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Schisler, john Q. (Methodist Board of Education, Nashville), 3 (1943-48, 1952) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Seigenthaler, John (The Nashville Tennessean), 1 (1967) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Shelby, T. H. (University of Texas), 2 (1939-40) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Showalter, B. R. (Alabama Polytechnic Institute), 1 (1941) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Smith, Lyn (Keep America Out of War Congress), 1 (1939) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Spaulding. C. C. (North Carolina Mutual Life Insurance Company), 1 (1943) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Spivey, Ludd M. (Florida Southern College), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Starks, J. J. (Benedict College), 1 (1943) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Stern, Edgar B., 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Stevens, Thelma (Women’s Missionary Council of the M.E. Church, South), 2 (1940, 1943) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Stevenson, John R. (Personal Assistant to John Foster Dulles), 1 (1952) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Stewart, Tom (United States Senate), 6 (1943-45, 1947) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Stigler, W. A. (Texas State Department of Education), 1 (1939) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Sutton, Pat (House of Representatives), 1 (1952) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Sutton, Willis (Atlanta Board of Education), 2 (1938) (1 to Mike Benton) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Sweets, Henry H. (Christian Education and Ministerial Relief of the Presbyterian Church), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Talmadge, Eugene (State of Georgia Executive Department), 1 (1935) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Tanner, Dudley (State of Tennessee Dept. of Education), 1 (1933) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Teilmann, Mrs. Gunnar J., Jr., 1 (1950) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Tenerowicz, Rudolph G. (House of Representatives), 1 (1941) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Thirkield, Wilbur P. (Methodist Episcopal Church), 1 (1928) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Thomas, Wilbur K. (American Friends Service Committee), 2 (1920) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Thompson, W. Taliaferro (Union Theological Seminary), 2 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Tobias, Channing H. (The National Council of the Young Men’s Christian Association), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Towner, Walter (General Board of Education of the Methodist Church), 1 (1946) (to H.H. Newsom) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Trabert, Charles L. (Newberry College), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Treanor, Paul W. (City of Nashville Commission Government), 1 (1919) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Upshaw, William D. (House of Representatives), 1 (1927) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Van Der Veer, McClellan (The Birmingham News), 1 (1939) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Walker, A. B., 1 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Washington, Forrester. B. (Atlanta University School of Social Work), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Waterfield, 1 (1922) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Watkins, Grace L. (University of Richmond), 1 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Weatherford, W. D. (Blue Ridge), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Weeks, Roger, 1 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Weems, Camilla (Georgia State College), 1 (1940) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - White, Walter (National Association for the Advancement of Colored People), 2 (1932, 1943) (1 to W. W. Alexander) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Whitaker, M. F. (State Agricultural and Mechanical College), 1 (1942) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Wilbourn, Margaret E. (Judson College), 1 (1939) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Wiley, Samuel S. (First Presbyterian Church, Anderson, S.C.), 1 (1950) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Winton, G. B. (Committee on Cooperation in Latin America), 2 (1917, 1921) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Woods, L. A. (Texas State Dept. of Education), 1 (1933) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Worden, Helen D. (Randolph-Macon College), 1 (1941) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Yeuell, Gladstone H. (University of Alabama), 1 (1941) (Box 1, Folder 17)